他们都讨厌你  曼达佬
They all hate you, Mando.
因为你是个传奇
Because you're a legend!
多少人有追踪器
How many had fobs?
他们都有
All of them.
他们要拿它怎么样
What's gonna happen to it?
我没问过
I didn't ask.
这有背公会准则
It's against the Guild Code.
前情回顾
索根星球
Sorgan.
没有星港  也没有工业中心  没有人口密集区
No star port, no industrial centers, no population density.
我要把他留在这里
I'm leaving him here.
和我一起流浪  这不是小孩该过的生活
Traveling with me, that's no life for a kid.
他们知道他在这
They know he's here.
是的
Yes.
他们会一直来找他的
Then they'll keep coming.
是的
Yes.
《星球大战》
把孩子交出来  曼达佬
Hand over the child, Mando.
也许我能放你一条生路
I might let you live.
抓紧了
Hold on.
来啊
Come on.
我能捉活的  也能捉死的
I can bring you in warm or I can bring you in cold.
那是我的台词
That's my line.
《曼达洛人》
第一季  第五章
杀手
燃料泄漏
Losing fuel.
这里是莫斯·埃斯利指挥塔
This is Mos Eisley Tower.
我们在追踪你
We are tracking you.
请将飞船停到到35号港  完毕
Head for bay three-five, over.
收到
Copy that.
锁定35号
Locked in for three-five.
嗨
Hey!
怎么回事
你打坏了我的一个机器人  你得赔偿
You damage one of my droids, you'll pay for it.
让它们离我的飞船远一点
Just keep them away from my ship.
是吗  你觉得这是个好主意吗
Yeah? You think that's a good idea, do ya?
看看你的飞船
Let's look at your ship.
看看这堆破烂
Oof! Look at that.
你这顶上有很多碳痕啊
Ugh, you got a lot of carbon scorin' building up top.
我乍一看  还以为你刚经历了一场交火
If I didn't know better, I'd think you were in a shootout.
得用专门的工具修
Special tool for that one.
我得把那里调一下
I am gonna have to rotate that.
你燃料泄漏了
You got a fuel leak.
看看那儿  真是一团糟
Look at that, this is a mess.
你怎么着陆的  要修这个可得劳你破费了
How did you even land? That's gonna set you back.
我这有500帝国信用点
I've got 500 Imperial Credits.
就这点
That's all you got?
你们觉得怎么样呢
Well, what do you guys think?
这应该够交你的停机费了
That should at least cover the hangar.
我会把钱付给你的
I'll get you your money.
这话我可没少听
Hmm. I've heard that before.
只要记住
Just remember...
不要机器人  听你说过了  不用再强调了
Yeah, no droids. I heard ya. You don't have to say it twice.
天啊
Jeez.
真是个混蛋
Womp rat.
我跟
I'm in.
再加三个螺栓和一个飞行舵
And I am gonna raise you three bolts and a motivator.
安静  快  把我的爆能步枪拿来
Shh. Quick, grab my blaster rifle.
如果我是你的话  我就会乖乖地待在飞船里
I'd stay in that ship if I were you.
什么
What?
过来  过来
Now, now.
让我好好瞧瞧你
Let Peli take a good look at you.
好样的  小乖乖
All right, there you go.
那个赏金猎人居然把你一个人丢在了这破飞船里
Did that bounty hunter leave you all alone in that big nasty ship?
我怎么知道这是什么东西  让我想想
How do I know what it is? Give me a second.
乖乖  你要吃点东西吗
All right. Now, would you like some food?
你饿了吗
Are you hungry?
拿点吃的来  快点
Okay. Fetch us something to eat. Quick!
我不知道  带骨头的就行
I don't know... Something with bones in it.
有了
Okay.
我知道怎么办了
Now, here's the plan.
我会一直照顾你到那个曼达洛人回来
I am going to look after you until The Mandalorian gets back,
然后我会额外收取他一些看护费
and then I'm gonna charge him extra for watching you.
懂了吗  大眼睛
You see how that works? Yeah, bright eyes?
我们是一伙的了
We're a team. Mmm-hmm.
机器人  我是名赏金猎人  想找份活干
Hey, droid, I'm a hunter. I'm lookin' for some work
可惜  塔图因的赏金猎人公会已经不复存在了
Unfortunately, the Bounty Guild no longer operates from Tatooine.
我不是找公会的工作
I'm not looking for Guild work.
但依我计算
I am afraid that does not improve your situation,
这也不会有什么改变
at least by my calculation.
再想想看  铁皮
Think again, tin can.
伙计  要找工作的话  不妨过来坐坐
If you're looking for work, have a seat, my friend.
我叫托罗  托罗·卡里肯
Name's Toro, Toro Calican.
来吧  别紧张
Come on, relax.
芬内克·尚德  悬赏价七十一万
这个赏金定位器是我离开中环之前领的
Picked up this Bounty Puck before I left the Mid Rim.
芬内克·尚德  一个刺客
Fennec Shand, an Assassin.
听说她自从新共和国将她的雇主们关押后
Heard she's been on the run ever since the New Republic
就一直在亡命奔逃
put all her employers in lockdown.
我听说过她
I know the name.
我跟着追踪器到这里
I followed this tracking fob here.
现在定位信息
Now the positional data
显示她朝着沙丘之海的方向去了
suggests she's headed out beyond the Dune Sea.
应该是份简单的活
Should be an easy job.
那就祝你好运了
Well, good luck with that.
等等  等等  我以为你需要找活干呢
Wait, wait, wait, hey. I thought you needed work?
你加入公会多久了
How long with the Guild?
很久了
Long enough.
很明显不是  芬内克·尚德是一名精英雇佣兵
Clearly not. Fennec Shand is an elite mercenary.
她因替顶尖犯罪集团杀人而成名
She made her name killing for all the top crime syndicates,
赫特人便是其中之一
including the Hutts.
如果你追杀她  你就看不到明天的太阳了
If you go after her, you won't make it past sunrise.
这是我第一份活
This is my first job.
你可以拿佣金  所有佣金
You can keep the money, all of it.
我得完成任务  才能加入公会
I just need this job to get into the Guild.
我一个人完成不了
I can't do it alone.
半小时内去35号港见我
Meet me at Hangar three-five in half an hour.
带两辆飞行摩托来  把追踪器给我
Bring two speeder bikes and give me the tracking fob.
别担心  我都记住了
Don't worry, got it all memorized.
半小时后见
Half an hour.
看来咱俩现在是一条绳上的蚂蚱了  伙计
Looks like you're stuck with me now, partner.
我很清醒  我没睡觉
I'm awake! I'm awake!
-他在哪里  -小点声
- Where is he? - Quiet!
乖乖别哭  你把他吵醒了
Oh. It's okay. You woke it up.
你知道我用了多久才把他哄睡的吗
Do you have any idea how long it took me to get it to sleep?
-把他给我  -别急啊
- Give him to me. - Not so fast!
你不能就那样把孩子一个人留下
You can't just leave a child all alone like that.
你完全不会带孩子
You know, you have an awful lot to learn about raisin' a young one.
好了  我已经开始修漏油的问题了
Anyway, I started the repair on the fuel leak.
就这样了
There you go.
我跟你说  修这玩意难度不小呢
I had a couple setbacks I want to talk to you about.
我按你要求的  没用机器人
You know, I didn't use any droids, as requested,
所以要修好比我预期的要更久
so it took me a lot longer than I expected.
但我想你应该不会吝啬额外费用吧
But I figured you were good for the money
毕竟还有一张嘴要养活呢
since you have an extra mouth to feed.
谢谢
Thank you.
我猜到了  你找到活干了  对吗
Oh, I guess I was right. You got a job, didn't you?
给这些机器人充电
You know, it's costing me a lot of money
都得花我不少钱
to keep these droids even powered up.
曼达佬  怎么样
Hey, Mando, what do you think?
还凑合吧
Not too shabby, huh?
你指望啥呢  这又不是科雷利亚  夫人你好
What'd you expect? This ain't Corellia. Ma'am.
-咋了  -前面有情况
- What's going on? - Look. Up ahead.
塔斯肯掠夺者
Tusken Raiders.
我听本地人讲过这些肮脏的家伙
I heard the locals talking about this filth.
塔斯肯人认为他们才是本地人
Tuskens think they're the locals.
其他人都是非法入侵的
Everyone else is just trespassing.
不管他们怎么看  最好离我们远点
Whatever they call themselves, they best keep their distance.
你自己跟他们说吧
Yeah? Why don't you tell them yourself?
放松
Relax.
-你在干嘛  -谈判
- What are you doing? - Negotiating.
什么情况
What's going on?
我们要通过他们的领地
We need passage across their land.
-把望远镜给我看看  -为什么
- Let me see the binocs. - Why?
搞啥啊
Hey! What?
那可是全新的
Those were brand new.
现在不是了
Yeah? They were.
趴下
Get down.
怎么了
What? Oh.
告诉我  你看到了什么
All right, tell me what you see.
湿背蜥
Dewback.
骑手好像被拖着在走
Looks like the rider is still attached.
是她吗  是我们的目标吗
Is that her? Is that the target?
我不知道
I don't know.
我去看看
I'll go.
你掩护我
You cover me.
记得趴下
Stay down.
是她吗  她死了吗
Well, is it her? Is she dead?
又是一个赏金猎人
It's another bounty hunter.
那些东西你别都拿了
Hey, I hope you don't plan on keeping all that stuff for yourself.
至少把爆能枪留给我吧
Can I at least have that blaster?
趴下
Get down!
曼达佬
Mando!
怎么了
What happened?
狙击枪
Sniper bolt.
只有改装过的MK型步枪才能打出如此一枪
Only an MK-modified rifle could make that shot.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
没事  只打中了盔甲
Yeah. Hit me in the beskar,
这种程度曼达洛铁还承受的来
and at that range beskar held up.
等下  我可没有曼达洛铁
Wait, I don't wear any beskar.
是没有
Nope.
那我们该怎么办
Well, so what do we do?
你有看见是从哪里打过来的吗
You see where that shot came from?
看到  在山脊那边打过来的
Yeah, it came from that ridge.
好吧  我们等到天黑
Okay, we're gonna wait until dark.
那她逃走了怎么办
Well, what if she escapes?
她可是在高地
She's got the high ground.
她会等我们先出手的
She'll wait for us to make the first move.
我先去休息
I'm gonna rest.
你守第一轮
You take the first watch.
别出去
Stay low!
好了  太阳下山了
All right, suns are down.
是时候出发了  曼达佬
Time to ride, Mando.
快点  快醒醒
Come on, wake up.
看看你
Look at you,
在任务途中睡着  老家伙
asleep on the job, old man.
玩够了吗
You done?
够了  我只是想
Yeah. I was just, you know,
叫醒你  快来吧
waking you up. Come on.
快上车
Get on your bike.
尽可能骑快点去到山石那边
Ride as fast as you can towards those rocks.
这就是你的计划
That's your plan?
她能直接把我们从车上射下来
She'll snipe us right off the bikes.
这是闪光弹
It's a flash charge.
我们交替射击
We alternate shots,
这能暂时让她失去视野
it'll blind any scope temporarily.
这样的话  我们加速前进还是有机会的
Combine that with our speed and we got a chance.
有机会
A chance?
是你想要这么做的
Hey, you wanted this.
做好准备
Get ready.
射击
Now!
别急着开枪啊  芬内克
Not so fast, Fennec.
注意力分散得好
Nice distraction.
搭档  干得漂亮啊
Yeah, good work, partner.
把自己铐上
Cuff yourself.
去拿那支爆能枪
Why don't you go find your blaster?
曼达洛人
A Mandalorian.
我已经很久没有见到曼达洛人了
It's been a long time since I've seen one of your kind.
去过内瓦罗吗
Ever been to Nevarro?
我听说那里发生的事情着实不咋样啊
I hear things didn't go so well there, but...
但看起来你倒是轻松脱身了
it looks like you got off easy.
我们把你抓起来  你就不用担心
You don't have to worry about gettin' to Nevarro,
内瓦罗或者其他地方了
or anywhere else, once we turn you in.
你知道吗  我真该好好谢谢你
You know, I really should thank you.
你就是我进入公会的门票
You're my ticket into the Guild.
不客气
You're welcome.
哦吼  看来我们其中一个必须步行了
Uh oh. Looks like one of us has to walk.
或者我们可以把你拖过去
Or we could drag you.
好吧  计划是什么
All right, so what is the plan?
你去找之前那只湿背蜥
I need you to go find that dewback we saw.
然后你和我的车还有悬赏目标留在这里
And leave you here with my bounty and my ride?
我看不行  曼达佬
Yeah, I don't think so, Mando.
好吧  那我去
Okay, I'll do it.
看紧她  别让她靠近车
Watch her, and don't let her get near the bike.
她死了对我们没有好处
She's no good to us dead.
过了挺久的了呀
Oh, it's been a while.
看  太阳都升起来了
Oh, look, the suns are coming up.
安静
Quiet.
听着  我现在还有时间
Look, there's still time to make
去莫斯埃斯帕赴约
my rendezvous in Mos Espa.
把我带到那儿去
Take me to it and I can pay
我可以给你两倍悬赏我的钱
you double the price on my head.
我才不想要钱
I don't care about the money.
那么那个曼达洛人把钱都自己留着咯
Oh, so the Mandalorian keeps all the money for himself.
那是因为我允许他那么做的
Only because I let him.
似乎不是这样吧
Doesn't seem that way.
我是说  好像事情都是他做主吧
I mean, it seems like he's calling all the shots.
那只是你自己觉得的
Shows what you know.
我雇了那个曼达佬  这是我的活
I hired Mando, this is my job.
把你抓起来
Bringin' you in will make
能让我成为赏金猎人公会的正式成员
me a full member of the Bounty Hunters Guild.
你已经有了对于公会来说比我更值钱的东西
You already have something the Guild values far more than me.
你只是还不知道而已
You just don't see it.
-什么  -那个曼达洛人
- What? - The Mandalorian.
光是他的盔甲就比我的酬金还值钱了
His armor alone's worth more than my bounty.
我已经告诉你了  我不想要钱
I already told you, I don't care about the money.
那名望呢
Then think what it would do for your reputation.
一个曼达洛人在内瓦罗袭击了公会
A Mandalorian shot up the Guild on Nevarro,
带走了价值极高的目标然后逃走了
took some high value target and went rogue.
那个曼达洛人吗
That Mandalorian?
就像我说的  曼达洛人可不常见
Like I said, you don't see many.
你把那个叛徒带去给公会
You bring the Guild that traitor,
他们就会张开怀抱欢迎你
and they'll welcome you with open arms.
你将成为一代传奇
Your name will be legendary.
我们怎么确定他就是公会想要的人
How can we be sure he's the one?
传言那个目标还在他手里
Word is, he still has the target with him.
有人说那是个孩子
Some say it's a child.
听着  如果你不敢挑战他  别怕
Look, if you're afraid to take him on, fear not.
我会帮助你的
I can help you with that.
听我一句劝  孩子
Take some advice, kid.
你想成为赏金猎人吗
You wanna be a bounty hunter?
将自己的利益最大化  然后努力活下去
Make the best deal for yourself and survive.
不错的建议
That's good advice,
但是如果我把手铐给你摘下来
but if I took those binders off of you
我就活不了了
I'd be a dead man.
但是如果曼达洛人的价值
And if the Mandalorian's worth
比你要高的多  那么
more than you are, well...
谁不想成为传奇呢
Who wouldn't want to be a legend?
谢谢你的建议
Thanks for the tip.
你终于回来了  曼达佬
Took you long enough, Mando.
看起来现在是我说了算  是吧搭档
Looks like I'm calling the shots now. Huh, partner?
放下你的爆能枪  举起手来
Drop your blaster and raise 'em.
把他铐起来
Cuff him.
你是公会的叛徒  曼达佬
You're a Guild traitor, Mando.
而且我敢打赌
And I'm willing to bet that
这就是那个你帮着逃跑的目标
this here is the target you helped escape.
你比你看起来要聪明
You're smarter than you look.
芬内克说得对
Fennec was right.
把你上交不仅能让我成为公会一员
Bringing you in won't just make me a member of the Guild,
还会让我成为传奇
it'll make me legendary.
-后退  -得找到他
- Stay back. - Gotta get it.
他在哪
Where is it?
你在这呢
There you are.
你在跟我们藏猫猫吗
Are you hiding from us? Huh?
看看你
Look at you.
-没关系  -我知道
- That's all right. - I know.
那声音对你大大的耳朵来说太吵了对吧
That was really loud for your big old ears, wasn't it?
没关系的
It's okay. Shh.
小心一点
Be careful with him.
所以我猜你没有得到报酬
So, I take it you didn't get paid?
这些够了吗
That cover me?
是的  当然足够了
Yeah. Yes, this is gonna cover you.
好了  机器人
All right, Pit Droids!
把这个拖出去
Let's drag this outta here!
我哪知道  就把他拖到乞丐谷吧
I don't know, drag it to Beggar's Canyon.